Michael Stokley

Seattle, WA

(303) 801-8575 • ⋈ michael@michaelstokley.com • ⋈ michaelstokley.com • in mastokley mastokley

Profile

Software developer. I'm patient enough to take difficult projects seriously, and driven enough to automate tedious, needlessly manual work. In my previous accounting position, I greatly exceeded expectations by teaching myself SQL and relational database theory in order to automate the vast majority of my data entry and data quality tasks, and avoid using a cumbersome GUI. Since then, I spent two years studying math, computer science, and statistics at North Seattle College, attended Code Fellows' Python Development Intensive (taught by esteemed pythonista Cris Ewing), and have independently studied the classic textbook The Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs. Recently, I helped to co-found a local big data/nlp startup, and have been working as a freelance web developer.

Technical Skills

Proficient Familiar

Python, Django, Django REST Framework, Pyramid, Git, SQL, AWS Deployment, Heroku Deployment, Ansible, PostgreSQL, Nginx, HTML/CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, Unix systems, Shell Scripting, Org- Gunicorn, Scheme, Sed mode, Regular Expressions

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

Red Mountain Software, Seattle, WA

2016.08 - 2016.10

Designed, built, and tested an internal management application according to client specification. App built with Django and PostgreSQL, with jQuery on the front as needed.

- Designed and implemented database schema
- Wrote models, views, and templates
- o Wrote a method to display arbitrary model fields (including reverse relationships) for arbitrary models

Co-founding Software Developer

Sternshus, Inc. Seattle, WA

2016.07 - 2016.09

Provided front-end solutions in the context of rapidly changing business requirements. Worked primarily in Webflow, Django, and MySQL. I am most proud of having written sed and python scripts to automate merging Webflow files into the larger Django project.

AR Specialist

Cleanscapes, Seattle, WA

2012.04 - 2015.04

- o Wrote and maintained a library of accurate, sophisticated SQL queries to capture evolving data inconsistencies; these queries eliminated 37.5 labor hours per month despite at 126% increase in customer accounts over a two year period
- o Designed database reports for internal and external customers, such as government officials and senior management
- Delegated data entry and data revision tasks
- Collaborated with operations, data quality, payment processing, and customer service teams to analyze and improve processes as new city contracts

Projects

Reciprocity

github.com/TeamReciprocity/reciprocity

2016 04

A full stack Python web application for recipe sharing and collaboration. Built with Django and PostgreSQL, deployed via Ansible to an AWS EC2 instance.

Toy Domain Scraper

github.com/mastokley/toy_domain_scraper

2016.04

Toy web scraper built in Python. Uses breadth-first traversal for fast, reliable results.

HomeQuest

github.com/homequest/homequest

2016.04

A full-stack Python web application to gamify household chores and chore management. Manually implemented authorization, authentication, and row-level security. Built in Pyramid with a PostgreSQL database and deployed on Heroku.

Education

Code Fellows Seattle, WA Certificate

Advanced Python development emphasizing test driven development, pair programming, agile methodologies, version control, and basic data structures

and algorithms North Seattle College Seattle, WA

Coursework in Math, Computer Science, and Statistics

2012-2014

2009

Annapolis, MD

St. John's College B. A. in Philosophy